SERN will take the time machine.
（桐生萌郁(きりゅうもえか)）
タイムマシンはＳＥＲＮ(セルン)が回収する
SERN? What do you mean?
（牧瀬紅莉栖(まきせくりす)）
ＳＥＲＮ？ どういうこと？
Makise Kurisu.
（萌郁）牧瀬紅莉栖
岡部倫太郎(おかべりんたろう)　橋田 至(はしだいたる)
Okabe Rintarou.
Hashida Itaru.
You three are coming with me.
３名は一緒に来てもらう
（橋田）ああ…
（岡部）ま… まゆりは？
What about Mayuri?
Shiina Mayuri is...
（萌郁）椎名(しいな)まゆりは…
...not needed.
必要ない
Don't.
やめろ…
やめてくれ
Don't do it.
For FB... FB... FB...
ＦＢのために…
ＦＢ ＦＢ！
（岡部）あっ ああ…
Mayuri?
まゆり？
Mayuri!
まゆり！
Mayuri?
まゆり？
What the fuck is this?!
何だよ これ
Get away from her.
（萌郁）離れて
Okabe, get away from her!
（紅莉栖）岡部 離れて！
岡部も殺されちゃう！
She'll kill you too!
You'll pay for this.
（岡部）許さない！
I'll make her pay for this!
俺が あいつを…
（阿万音鈴羽(あまねすずは)）はあっ！
（ラウンダー１）うわあ
（鈴羽）えい！
（ラウンダー２）ぐわっ
Forty-two.
（鈴羽）42
CRT.
ブラウン管
It's on.
点灯済み
（鈴羽）うぐっ… 早く！
Hurry!
（紅莉栖）ハア ハア…
岡部？
Okabe!
俺が行く
I'll go!
But if it fails...
でも もし失敗したら…
Do it now!
（岡部）早くしろ！
うっ
Okabe!
岡部！
（紅莉栖）うわっ
Leap!
（岡部）飛べよおおっ！
～
Metaphysics
Necrosis
Mayuri was still in elementary school...
（岡部）
まゆりの祖母が亡くなったのは
...when her grandmother died.
まだ まゆりが小学生のころだった
She went to her grave every day.
まゆりは
毎日 墓参りを欠かさず―
Even six months after her grandmother's death,
それは祖母が亡くなって
半年たっても続いていた
she kept going.
形見の懐中時計を手に
She always had her grandmother's
pocket watch in her hand,
and she was always, always looking up at the sky...
いつも いつも 空を見上げていた
まるで 祖母が迎えに来るのを
待っているように
...like she was waiting for
her grandmother to come and get her.
And then one day, there was a ray of light.
そんなある日 光は射した
It was the kind called Rembrandt lighting...
レンブラント光線
...or an angel's ladder.
エンジェルラダーとも呼ばれる光
It felt like the light was drawing her up...
まゆりが その光に
引き込まれていくような―
...like she was going to disappear...
このまま
まゆりが消えてしまうような…
（岡部）まゆり！
Mayuri!
Okarin...
（まゆり）オカリン？
I won't let it take you.
（岡部）連れてなんていかせない
You're going to be my hostage.
まゆりは俺の人質だ
I'll use you for human experimentation.
人体実験の いけにえなんだ
The words that came out of my mouth
（岡部）口をついて出たのは
were from some show I'd seen as a little kid.
ガキのころ覚えた そんなセリフ
Mayuri and I had watched it together.
まゆりと２人で見たテレビで―
Some mad scientist, screaming like an idiot...
マッドサイエンティストが
バカみたいに叫んでたセリフ
I see.
（まゆり）そっかあ
So Mayushii is your hostage, right?
まゆしぃは
オカリンの人質なんだね
Then I guess I can't go, huh?
じゃあ しょうがないね
（紅莉栖）ん？
（岡部）うっ ハアッ ハアッ
What's wrong?
（紅莉栖）どうしたの？
Were you napping?
もしかして 居眠りでもしてた？
What time is it?
（岡部）今は何時だ？
（紅莉栖）えっ？
（岡部）何時だ？
What time is it?!
What?
何よ？
もうすぐ５時
It's almost five.
You're going shopping, right?
買い物に行くんでしょ？
Shopping...
買い物？
I'll order pizza.
（橋田）
じゃあ 僕は ピザ注文しておくよ
Thanks.
（紅莉栖）お願い
トロピカルスペシャルだけは―
Just don't get the tropical special.
やめてね
あれ苦手なの
I hate that thing.
Agreed.
（橋田）同意
The time leap worked?
成功したのか？ タイムリープに
Okabe?
（紅莉栖）岡部？
Where's Mayuri?
まゆりは？ まゆりは どこだ？
Where is she?!
What's wrong with you all of a sudden?
（紅莉栖）
何なのよ？ やぶから棒に
Mayushii said she was going to Miss Ruka's
to invite her to the party, remember?
まゆ氏なら るか氏のとこに
パーティー誘いにいくって―
さっき出ていったじゃん
あ… 買い物 行くの？
Are you going shopping?
The development conference is canceled.
（岡部）開発評議会は中止だ
Canceled?
中止？ どうして？
Why?
Did something happen?
（橋田）何かあったん？
We're done here for today.
（岡部）今日は これで解散だ
Both of you, go home now!
２人とも すぐ家に帰れ
（紅莉栖）どういうこと？
What's going on?
（岡部）いいから帰るんだ！
いいな 絶対だ！
Just go home!
Okay? Just do it!
What's with him?
何なの？
His phone starts ringing, and then...
携帯が かかってきたと思ったら
ハッ
Phone?
携帯？
（まゆり）
トゥットゥルー！ まゆしぃです
This is Mayushii.
I can't answer the phone right now!
今 電話に出られません
If you'd like to leave a message—
ご用の方は…
There's nothing to indicate
that the world line changed.
（岡部）
世界線が大きく変わった様子はない
It's different from a D-mail.
Ｄメールのときとは違って―
I really am back at 5:00 PM.
本当に
今日の午後５時に戻ってきたんだ
（男の子）ガタンガタン 新幹線！
It's the bullet train!
No, the bullet train is white.
（母親）
違うでしょ 新幹線は白いの
After this, Mayuri will return with Suzuha.
（岡部）このあと まゆりが
鈴羽を連れて帰ってきて…
Should I go to the police?
（岡部）警察に駆け込むか？
No, who would believe me?
いや 誰が信じる？
未来から
タイムリープしてきたなんて
That I've come from the future?
Three hours left...
あと３時間で 何とかするしかない
I have to do something!
（岡部）まゆり
Mayuri!
まゆり！
Mayuri?!
（漆原(うるしばら)るか）
あっ 岡… いえ 凶真(きょうま)さん
O-Oka... No, Kyouma—
Where's Mayuri?!
まゆりは どこだ！
（るか）えっ？
あっ もう帰りましたけど
Sh-She already left.
Left?
帰った？ いつだ？
When?
Th-Thirty minutes ago, I guess.
（るか）
さっ 30分くらい前でしょうか
She said she was going back to the lab.
“ラボに戻る”って
言ってましたけど
Didn't she get back?
戻ってないんですか？
Um, I'm sorry.
あの すみません
It was so nice of you to
invite me to the party, but—
せっかく パーティーに
誘ってもらったのに―
僕 今日は どうしても…
Did she say she was stopping anywhere?
（岡部）どこかに寄るとは
言ってなかったか？
えっ？ まゆりちゃんですか？
Mayuri?
いえ
No...
If you see her, tell her to call me right away!
（岡部）もし 見かけたら
すぐ俺に電話するように言ってくれ
O-Okay.
はっ はい
If the world line hasn't changed...
（岡部）世界線が変わっていない
ということは
If I don't do anything differently,
まゆり自身の行動は―
俺が何かをしないかぎり
変わらないはずだ
she should do what she did before.
どこだ？
Where is she?
Meow-meow!
（フェイリス）ニャンニャン
Feyris can't answer the phone right now.
フェイリスは
今 電話に出られないニャ
If you need something—
（岡部）くっ
どこにいるんだ？ まゆり
Where are you, Mayuri?
まゆりか？
Mayuri?
Too bad.
（紅莉栖）おあいにくさま
助手か
Assistant...
I told you that we were done for the day.
今日はもう解散だと言っただろう
Go home—
（岡部）早く帰って…
（紅莉栖）端的に答えて
Be honest.
You time leaped from the future, didn't you?
（紅莉栖）あんた 未来から
タイムリープしてきたんじゃない？
（岡部）なっ…
How could you tell?
なぜ分かった？
The second you answered the phone,
you seemed to change.
（紅莉栖）携帯に出た瞬間
人が変わったみたいになったから
From the way you're acting,
その様子だと
何かあったってこと？
I can guess that something happened.
（岡部）ああ
Yeah...
だが詳しく話している時間はない
...but I don't have time to give you the details.
Just run.
とにかく逃げるんだ
Run? Where?
（紅莉栖）逃げるって どこに？
Anywhere.
（岡部）どこでもいい
なるべく ラボから離れるんだ
Just get away from the lab.
Got it?
分かったな
Tell me later, okay?
（紅莉栖）
あとで ちゃんと聞かせてよ
Yeah.
（岡部）ああ ダルにも伝えてくれ
Tell Daru too.
Got it.
（紅莉栖）分かった
岡部…
Okabe...
（岡部）なんだ？
What is it?
Don't do anything stupid.
（紅莉栖）変なことは しないでね
I know.
分かってる
Okabe Rintarou!
（鈴羽）岡部倫太郎
Hey, where's Ochanomizu—
あのさあ 御茶ノ水(おちゃのみず)って…
（岡部）まゆりを見てないか？
Have you seen Mayuri?!
あっ 椎名まゆり？
Shiina Mayuri?
ああ ちょうど今
パーティーに誘われて…
She just invited me to your party—
（岡部）どこだ！
Where is she?
Turn right, up there...
そこを右 曲がったとこで…
ああっ
ねえ 御茶ノ水ってどっち？
Hey, which way is Ochanomizu?
I have to take Nae shopping...
綯(なえ)が買い物 行くから
送ってかなきゃなんだけど
Ask at the police substation!
（岡部）道なら交番で聞け！
And once you've taken her, don't come back!
それと 送ったら
お前も戻ってくるな！
どういうこと？
What do you mean?
I'll tell you later.
（岡部）理由は あとで話す！
（鈴羽）ふうっ
まゆり
Mayuri...
まゆり！
Mayuri!
あっ オカリン
Okarin!
Look! It's the first star!
見て！ 一番星
わっ 何？
What?
Just come with me!
いいから 一緒に来るんだ
（まゆり）えっ？ パーティーは？
What about the party?
It was canceled. I told Kurisu and Daru.
中止だ！
もう紅莉栖とダルにも言ってある
（まゆり）ええっ どうして？
Why?
I'll tell you later!
（岡部）あとで説明する
（まゆり）
でも 鈴(すず)さん誘っちゃったし―
But I asked Suzu to come too,
and Daru was ordering pizza...
ダル君だってピザ頼むって…
Just listen to me!
いいから 言うことを聞け！
Okarin...
オカリン
I'm sorry.
すまない
まゆしぃは よく分からないのです
Mayushii doesn't understand...
You always do things I don't understand,
オカリンは いつも
よく分からないことするけど―
but today, I really don't understand you.
今日のオカリンは
ホントに分からないよ
Did you really want to
do the experiment, after all?
実験 やっぱり
やりたかったのかな？
Mayuri...
まゆり
That's not it.
そういうわけじゃない
But just for now, can you listen to me?
でも 今は
言うとおりにしてくれないか？
There's no time.
時間がないんだ
I'll explain the details later. I promise.
詳しいことは
あとでちゃんと話す
Okay.
うん
Sorry. Mayushii just got scared.
ごめんね まゆしぃ
なんかビックリしちゃって
Don't apologize.
（岡部）謝るな まゆりは悪くない
It's not your fault.
There are so many people here.
すごい人だね
It's rush hour.
帰宅ラッシュの時間だからな
Huh?
（まゆり）あれっ？
でも 誰もいないよ ホーム
But no one's at the platform...
ハッ！
Once again,
（アナウンス）
もう一度 お伝えします
爆破の予告があったために
the following lines have been shut down,
due to a bomb threat.
現在 運転を見合わせて
いるのは次の路線です
They said they don't know when
the trains will start again.
（男性）運転再開の
めどはまだ出てないって
How stupid of me!
なんて うかつな！
こんなときに
Not now...
オカリン？
Okarin?
Mayuri, get to the subway now!
まゆり 地下鉄だ！ 早く…
Okabe Rintarou, right?
（ラウンダー３）
岡部倫太郎だな？
どうしたの？
What's wrong?
You're coming with me.
（ラウンダー３）
一緒に来てもらう
What are you standing there for?
（男性）そこ 何 止まってんだよ
Move!
どいてくれ！
Run!
（岡部）走れ！
（まゆり）えっ？ ああっ
（岡部とまゆりの荒い息）
走れ！ 全力で走るんだ
Run!
Run as fast as you can!
Who are they?
（まゆり）あの人たちは？
（岡部･まゆり）うわっ
Okarin!
（まゆり）オカリン！
（岡部）早く行け！
Go, quickly!
Run, Mayuri!
逃げろ まゆり！
（まゆり）ひっ…
ああ…
Shiina Mayuri was the one who died.
死んだのは椎名まゆりです
Okabe...
岡部君 いえ
岡部倫太郎は確保しました
I mean, Okabe Rintarou has been captured.
（岡部）まゆり
Mayuri!
Damn it!
クソオオオ！
I won't let you kill her!
殺させない
Mayuri, I will save you!
まゆり 絶対に助けてやる
（岡部）お前を…
I'll save you...
...no matter what!
必ず！
Canceled?
（紅莉栖）中止？ どうして？
Why?
（橋田）何かあったん？
Did something happen?
Yeah. Actually...
（岡部）ああ 実はなあ―
I got word that Mr. Braun is planning to return tonight.
ミスターブラウンが―
今晩 乗り込んでくるという情報を
キャッチした
Okarin, did you do something again?
オカリン
また何かやらかしたん？
Yeah, I suppose so.
ああ ちょっとな
でも まゆりは…
But what about Mayuri?
I'll talk to her.
まゆりには俺が言う
とにかく ここにいては危険だ
It's dangerous to be here.
本日は解散とする
We're done here for today.
（岡部）強引すぎたか？
Was I too forceful?
No...
いや 怪しかろうと何だろうといい
It doesn't matter if I was acting weird.
For now, I just need them away from the lab!
とにかく 今は―
みんなを
ラボから遠ざけるのが先だ！
（まゆり）
トウットゥルー！ まゆしぃです
This is Mayushii.
今 電話に出られません
I can't answer the phone right now!
Why is it taking so long?
（岡部）
どうしても時間がかかってしまう
It's going to end up like last time!
これじゃあ さっきと同じだ
何とかして まゆりを…
I need to find Mayuri.
あっ
Rukako
（るか）もしもし
Hello?
るか子 俺だ 岡部だ
Rukako! It's me! Okabe!
（るか）あっ 岡…
いえ すみません 凶真さん
Oka... I'm sorry, Kyouma—
Where's Mayuri?!
まゆりは？
まゆりは そこにいるか？
Is Mayuri there?
Mayuri?
（るか）
まゆりちゃんですか？
はい 今 帰るところで…
Yes.
She's just heading bac—
Stop her!
（岡部）呼び止めるんだ！
Tell her not to move until I get there!
俺が行くまで 絶対に
そこから動くなと伝えてくれ
でも ラボに戻るって
She said she was going back to the lab.
（岡部）いいから
言うとおりにするんだ！
Just do as I say!
は… はい
O-Okay.
まゆりちゃーん
Mayuri!
（まゆり）ん？
（男の子）ガタンガタン 新幹線
It's the bullet train!
No, the bullet train is white.
（母親）
違うでしょ 新幹線は白いの
Mayuri!
（岡部）まゆり！
Okarin!
（まゆり）ああ オカリン
トゥットゥルー
（岡部の荒い息）
Are you okay?
（まゆり）大丈夫？
I was about to go fix Fubuki's costume
これから
フブキちゃんのコス直して―
ラボに帰るところだったのに
and then go to the lab.
Fubuki?
フブキちゃん？ コスプレ仲間か？
A cosplay friend of yours?
Yeah!
（まゆり）うん まゆしぃが作った
コスの糸がほつれちゃったんだって
She said a thread on the costume
I made came undone.
I just got a message from her.
今 メールがあって…
So that's it.
（岡部）そういうことだったのか
Once it's fixed, I'll go right to the lab,
直したら すぐラボに行くから―
so I'll make it to the party.
パーティーには間に合うよ
Wait. The party...
（岡部）待て！ パーティーは…
パーティーは中止…
The party was cancel—
延期になった
I mean, it was postponed.
（まゆり）ええっ どうして？
Why?
We can't use the lab...
どうしても
ラボが使えなくなってな
...due to unforeseen consequences.
しかたないんだ
I see...
そうなんだ
So I wanted you to come with me for a bit.
（岡部）それで 今から まゆりには
ちょっとつきあってもらいたい
Right now.
今すぐだ
（まゆり）フブキちゃんは？
What about Fubuki?
I'm sorry, but save it for later.
（岡部）すまんが あとにしてくれ
大至急なんだ
This is an emergency.
（るか）
あの 何かあったんですか？
Um, did something happen?
Yeah, we're going away for a while.
（岡部）ああ
これから ちょっと遠出する
旅行だ
On a trip.
えっ？ ふ… 二人でですか？
Together?
Um, well...
いえ その…
うう… フブキちゃんは
あしたでもいいけど―
I can put Fubuki off until tomorrow,
but this is very sudden.
急だね
Where are we going?
どこに行くの？
I'll tell you later.
（岡部）それは あとで話す
電車の時間がないんだ
We don't have much time to catch the train.
But Mayushii isn't ready at all, and—
でも まゆしぃ
何の準備もしてないし―
（まゆり）お金も…
（岡部）それは心配しなくていい
Don't worry about it.
Come on, let's go.
（岡部）さあ 行くぞ
（まゆり）あっ
（まゆり）待ってよ オカリン
Wait, Okarin!
（るか）あっ あの…
Um...
え？
Huh?
G-Goodbye.
（るか）いっ いってらっしゃい
Yeah, bye-bye!
うん いってくるね
（るか）ああ…
Isn't Akihabara Station that way?
（まゆり）秋葉原(あきはばら)の駅
向こうじゃないかなあ？
We're taking the subway.
地下鉄で行く
I see.
そうなんだ
It's been a really long time since you dragged me along like this.
（まゆり）なんか こうやって
オカリンに引っ張られて歩くの―
すごい久しぶりだね
ああ…
Yeah.
あっ
戻るぞ
We're heading back.
Huh?
え？
よし 行くぞ
Okay.
Let's go.
From: Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Kurisu, huh?
紅莉栖か
（まゆり）あれえ？
まゆしぃの懐中 止まっちゃってる
My watch isn't working...
おかしいな
さっき ネジ巻いたばっかりなのに
That's strange.
I just wound it.
There are so many people here.
ずいぶん人が多いね
The Sobu line shut down.
総武(そうぶ)線が止まったんだろう
えっ？ 止まってるの？
Shut down?
ああ
Yeah.
A bomb threat was called in.
“爆弾を仕掛けた”という
電話が入ったらしくてな
I see...
そうなんだ
Hey, Okarin.
ねえ オカリン
Um, well...
あのね
まゆしぃは聞きたいことが
いっぱいあるけど―
Mayushii has a lot of questions she wants to ask,
but it's okay for now.
今は 我慢しとくね
In exchange,
その代わり 終わったら
全部 聞かせてほしいのです
when this is over,
I want you to tell me everything.
Yeah.
（岡部）ああ
I promise.
約束する
I'm sorry...
（まゆり）ごめんね
（岡部）えっ？
I'm sorry I can't help you.
（まゆり）
オカリンの力になれなくて
ごめんね
Let's have that party sometime.
パーティー いつかやろうな
Yeah...
（まゆり）うん いつか
Sometime.
Sometime...
いつか―
For sure.
必ず
（天王寺(てんのうじ) 綯）まゆりお姉ちゃん！
Big sis Mayuri!
（まゆり）ん？
（電車の警笛）
It wasn't...
（綯）…じゃないの
わざとじゃないの
I didn't mean to...
私 お姉ちゃんを―
I just wanted to surprise her...
ビックリさせようと思って…
I won't let you kill her!
（岡部）殺させない
まゆりは 俺が…
Mayuri, I will...
...save you!
助ける！
～